Guide to the Elsie H. Hillman Papers, 1920-2015 AIS.2013.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Subject Files, 1970-2014; VII.
  - Pro-Choice, 1970-2005; 3.
    - Topical Files, 1970-2009
      - Planned Parenthood of Western Pennsylvania, 70th Anniversary Celebration (at Hillman Residence), 2000 (Box 86, Folder 9)
      - Planned Parenthood of Western Pennsylvania, 75th Anniversary Celebration (at Hillman Residence), Newspaper Clipping and Program Booklet, 2000 (Box 86, Folder 10)
      - Pro-Life Materials, Newspaper Clippings, Newsletters and Magazine Articles, 1970-1972 (Box 86, Folder 11)
      - Pro-Life Materials, Women Concerned for the Unborn Child, 1970-1971 (Box 86, Folder 12)
      - Republican Pro Choice Bumper Stickers, c. 1992 (Box 86, Folder 13)
      - Republicans for Choice, Mailings, 1990-1992 (Box 86, Folder 14)
      - Ridge, Tom, 1993-1996 (Box 86, Folder 15)
      - Santorum, Rick, 1990-1991 (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - State Choice Developments, 1980-1986 (Box 86, Folder 17)
      - State Family Planning Budget, 1995-1997 (Box 86, Folder 18)
      - State Senate Bill No. 646, 1990 (Box 86, Folder 19)
      - Stem Cell Research, 1990 (Box 86, Folder 20)
      - Washington March for Choice, Newspaper Clipping, 1989 (Box 86, Folder 21)
      - WISH Breakfast Club Pamphlet, 1992 (Box 86, Folder 22)
      - Women's Health Service Dinner, Newspaper Clipping, 1989 (Box 86, Folder 23)
  - Other Topics, 1920-2014; 4.
    Subseries 4 contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, article packets, and other records relating to Elsie Hillman's interest in numerous other topics and smaller organizations and institutions. They are arranged alphabetically by topic or organization.
    - Acid Rain, 1987 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Allegheny County 2001, Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1991 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Allegheny County 2001, Reports and Panel Recommendations, 1991-1992 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Allegheny County New Form of Government, Call Reports, Memoranda, and Meeting Minutes, 2000 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Allegheny County New Form of Government, Correspondence, 2000 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Allegheny County Tourism Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - American Family Foundation, 1983 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - American Jewish Committee, Louis Caplan Human Relations Award Panel of Judges, 1996 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Another Side Inc., Newsletters and Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - ARC-Allegheny Foundation, 1996 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Big Brothers, 1972 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Binstock, Dorothy, Newspaper Clipping, 1982 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - B'nai Brith, 2002 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - C. Howard Marcey State Hospital, 1981 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Calvary Episcopal Church, Capital Funds Campaign Proposal and Report, 1971 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Calvary Episcopal Church, Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - Canada Forum, 2004-2005 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - Carnegie Library and Multi-Purpose Center, Invitation to Board of Trustees, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - Carnegie Mellon University, College of Humanities and Social Sciences, 1973 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - Carnegie Mellon University, Highlands Circle, 2005 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Carnegie Mellon University Hillman Center, Magazines, 2009-2010 (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - Carnegie Mellon University Hillman Center, Newspaper Clippings, 2009 (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - Center for the American Woman and Politics, 1973 (Box 87, Folder 23)
    - Children and Youth Projects Funding, 1981 (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - Children's Hospital Circle of Care and Frank LeMoyne Society, "An Evening at the Frick", 2009 (Box 87, Folder 25)
    - Children's Hospital Foundation, Newspaper Article, 2005 (Box 87, Folder 26)
    - Citizen's Advisory Committee, 1970 (Box 87, Folder 27)
    - Citizens For America, Article Packets and Newspaper Clippings, 1983-1985 (Box 87, Folder 28)
    - Citizens for America, Information Packets and Mailings, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 29)
    - City of Hope National Medical Center, 1974 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Club for Growth, 2004-2006 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Coalition for Addictive Diseases in Southwest Pennsylvania, 1982-1984 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Coalition to Improve State and Local Government, Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Coalition to Improve State and Local Government, Programs and Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Coalition to Improve State and Local Government, Work Plans and Papers, 1987-1989 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - College Club of Pittsburgh, Speaking Event, 1971 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Colville, Bob, 1974-1975 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Commission on Presidential Debates, Pittsburgh Site Inspection, 1987 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Committee for Integrated Schools, 1972 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Committee for National Security, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Community Foundation for Greater Johnstown, Flower Barn Fund, 1992-1993 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Cooperative East End Ministry, "Two Pianos, Four Hands," Program Book, 2009 (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Corporate Alliance for Drug Education, 2005 (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Costa, Johnny, 1993-1995 (Box 88, Folder 15)
    - David Lawrence Convention Center, Budgets and Expenditures, 2002-2003 (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - David Lawrence Convention Center, Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - David Lawrence Convention Center, Memoranda, 2002-2003 (Box 88, Folder 18)
    - David Lawrence Convention Center, Newspaper Articles and Press Releases, 2002-2003 (Box 88, Folder 19)
    - Davis School Graziano Bros Development, undated (Box 88, Folder 20)
    - Distinguished Daughters of Pennsylvania, Annual Award Luncheon Program, 2002 (Box 88, Folder 21)
    - Drug and Alcohol Abuse, Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 88, Folder 22)
    - Drug and Alcohol Abuse, Newspaper Clippings and Informational Materials, 1982 (Box 88, Folder 23)
    - Drug and Alcohol Abuse, Testimonials and House Bill 2533, 1982 (Box 88, Folder 24)
    - Duquesne University School of Business and Administration, 1972-1973 (Box 88, Folder 25)
    - Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, 1992-1994 (Box 88, Folder 26)
    - Ellis School, Election as Honorary Trustee, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 27)
    - Environment, 1979-1984 (Box 88, Folder 28)
    - Executive Report Magazine, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 29)
    - Extra Mile Foundation, 1999 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Family Philanthropy Conference, 1999 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Four Chaplains Memorial Foundation, Invitation to Board of Directors, 2008 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Friends of Hopital Albert Schweitzer Haiti, Haitian Art Benefit, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Fulton Scholarships, 1975-1976 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Gammage Case, Memoranda, 1996 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Gammage Case, Press Releases, Newspaper Clippings and Related Materials, 1995-1996 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Gateway Rehabilitation, Abraham Twersky, 1983-1985 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Gateway Rehabilitation, Hope Has a Home Gala, 2009 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Gettysburg College, Eisenhower Society and Institute, 1990-1994 (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Girls Scouts-Madeline Albright Event, 2011 (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Girl Scouts-Trillium Council, Women and Girls of Distinction Awards, 2007 (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Good Government Awards, 2014 (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Government Study Commission of Pittsburgh, 1974 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Grantmakers of Western Pennsylvania, 2005 (Box 89, Folder 15)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Commission for Women, Biennial Report, 1989-1990 (Box 89, Folder 16)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Commission for Women, Board Meeting Minutes and Bylaws, 1993 (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Commission for Women, Brochure and Press Materials, 1989 (Box 89, Folder 18)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Commission for Women, Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 89, Folder 19)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Commission for Women, Mission Statement and Overview of Projects, 1992-1994 (Box 89, Folder 20)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Commission for Women, Proposal for Enhancing Women's Business Development and Opportunities for Funding Such Efforts in the Pittsburgh Region, 1992 (Box 89, Folder 21)
    - Greater Pittsburgh National Association of Women Business Owners, Meeting Ideas, 1994 (Box 89, Folder 22)
    - Greater Pittsburgh National Association of Women Business Owners, Thank You Note, 1985 (Box 89, Folder 23)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Religious Community, Comm-UNITY, For Hope Healing and Justice Program, 1996 (Box 89, Folder 24)
    - Guardians of Greater Pittsburgh Incorporated, 1973 (Box 89, Folder 25)
    - Gulf War, Correspondence and Attached Press Releases, 1990-1991 (Box 89, Folder 26)
    - Gulf War, Newspaper Clippings and Newsletters, 1990 (Box 89, Folder 27)
    - Gulf War, Newspaper Clippings, 1991 (Box 89, Folder 28-30)
    - Gun Control, Brady Bill, 1991 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Hatch Act, Statute and Proposals, 1991 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Health and Welfare Association of Allegheny County, Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Health and Welfare Association of Allegheny County, Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Health and Welfare Association of Allegheny County, Memoranda, 1971 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Health and Welfare Association of Allegheny County, Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1972 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Health and Welfare Association of Allegheny County, Proposed Budget, 1972 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Health and Welfare Association of Allegheny County, Report of the Reappraisal and Development Commission, 1972 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - H. John Heinz III School of Public Policy and Management, "Celebrating Partnerships in Pittsburgh", 2007 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Heinz History Center, "Brunch With Elsie Hillman" Event, 2006-2007 (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Heinz History Center, "First Ladies Exhibit", 2006 (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - Howard, Ed, 1979 (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Humanities in Pennsylvania, 1972 (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - International Poetry Forum, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Italian Sons and Daughters of America, 1975-1981 (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - I.W. Abel Testimonial Award Dinner, 1977 (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - Joint Center for Political and Economic Studies, Correspondence, 1989-1994 (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Joint Center for Political and Economic Studies, Institutional Development Campaign, Leadership Campaign Prospect Book, 1990-1994 (Box 90, Folder 18)
    - Joint Center for Political and Economic Studies, List of Solicitations for Funding, 1994 (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - Joint Center for Political and Economic Studies, Notes, c. 1989-1991 (Box 90, Folder 20)
    - Judicial Reform, Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 90, Folder 21-22)
    - Judicial Reform, Draft of Plan Submitted to Committee of Seventy, 1985 (Box 90, Folder 23)
    - Judicial Reform, Grant Application for Judicial Governance Project, 1983 (Box 90, Folder 24)
    - Judicial Reform, Judicial Selection Governance Study, 1983 (Box 90, Folder 25)
    - Judicial Reform, Newspaper Clippings and Magazine Articles, 1979-1984 (Box 90, Folder 26)
    - KDKA Program, 1972 (Box 90, Folder 27)
    - Keeping Women Healthy Program, 1997-1999 (Box 90, Folder 28)
    - Kiwanis Club, Pamphlet, 2011 (Box 90, Folder 29)
    - Leadership Pittsburgh, Alumni Directory, 1984-1986 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Leadership Pittsburgh, Correspondence, 1985 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Leadership Pittsburgh, Program Overview, 1994 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Leadership Pittsburgh, Reports and Seminar Programs, 1984-1986 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Lemington Home for the Aged, 1985-1986 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Lieberth, Charles, 1972-1974 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Lincoln Larimer Community Service Center/Kingsley Association, 2002 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Magee Women's Hospital, "A Celebration of Women" Event, 1999 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - McClelland, Sarah, 1924-1934 (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Missing Children Project, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Na'Amat USA, 1995 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Nard, John A., 1979-1984 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - National Association of Press Photographers, Suggested Title for Pennsylvania Primary Photo, 1979 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Brotherhood and Sisterhood Award Dinner, 1995 (Box 91, Folder 14)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Tribute Dinner for Arthur J. Edmunds, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 15)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Tribute Dinner Honoring Jim Roddey, 2002 (Box 91, Folder 16)
    - National Month of Unity, Proclamation Issued by President Bill Clinton, 1996 (Box 91, Folder 17)
    - National Women's Leadership Summit, 2002 (Box 91, Folder 18)
    - Neighbor Aid, Correspondence and Memoranda, 2008-2009 (Box 91, Folder 19)
    - Neighbor Aid, Fundraising, 2009 (Box 91, Folder 20)
    - Neighbor Aid, Meeting Minutes, 2008 (Box 91, Folder 21)
    - Neighbor Aid, Newspaper Articles and Press Releases, 2008-2009 (Box 91, Folder 22)
    - Neighbor Aid, Reports, 2008-2009 (Box 91, Folder 23)
    - New Pittsburgh Collaborative, 2003-2004 (Box 91, Folder 24)
    - "Off the Record" Musical Programs, 2001-2005 (Box 91, Folder 25)
    - Operation Better Block, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1971-1973 (Box 91, Folder 26)
    - Operation Better Block, Notes, 1970-1973 (Box 91, Folder 27)
    - Operation Better Block, Reports, 1970-1972 (Box 91, Folder 28)
    - Panther Hollow Bridge Rehabilitation Project, 1996-1997 (Box 91, Folder 29)
    - Passage to Power Women's Conference, 1978 (Box 91, Folder 30)
    - Peace Links Nuclear Disarmament Workshop, Agenda and Informational Materials, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 31)
    - Peace Links Nuclear Disarmament Workshop, Correspondence, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 32)
    - Peace Links Nuclear Disarmament Workshop, Newspaper Clippings and Magazine Articles, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 33)
    - Peace Links Nuclear Disarmament Workshop, Pamphlets and Booklets, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 34)
    - Peace Links Nuclear Disarmament Workshop, Speech by Hillman, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 35)
    - Pennsylvania Chamber Dinner, 1989 (Box 91, Folder 36)
    - Pennsylvania Coalition Against Rape, 2005 (Box 91, Folder 37)
    - Pennsylvania Governor's Conference for Women, Conference Program, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Pennsylvania Governor's Conference for Women, Correspondence and Thank You Notes, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Pennsylvania Governor's Conference for Women, Correspondence and Thank you Notes, 2008 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Pennsylvania Governor's Conference for Women, Planning Documents, 2008 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Pennsylvania Governor's Conference for Women, Remarks by Hillman, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania Governor's Conference for Women, Related Articles and Documentation, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Pennsylvania Governor's Conference for Women, Sponsor and Host Committee List, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania Governor's Conference for Women, Study of 2005 Conference, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Pennsylvania Society, Dinner Programs, 1998-2009 (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Pennsylvania Society, Recommendation of award to General Matthew Ridgeway, 1985 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Persad Center, Art for AIDS, 1996 (Box 92, Folder 11)
    - Phillips Hall, 1970 (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - "Pittsburgh 250", 2006 (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Pittsburgh Airport Finances, 2003 (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - "Pittsburgh, Beijing and Beyond", 1994-1995 (Box 92, Folder 15)
    - Pittsburgh Children's Museum Advisory Council, 1970 (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Pittsburgh Foundation, James G. Fulton Internship Fund, 1973 (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - Pittsburgh Free Clinic, 1970-1971 (Box 92, Folder 18)
    - Pittsburgh Fundraisers, 1997 (Box 92, Folder 19)
    - Pittsburgh International Airport, 1992-1993 (Box 92, Folder 20)
    - Pittsburgh Job Growth, 1992-1993 (Box 92, Folder 21)
    - Pittsburgh National Association for Female Executives, 1984 (Box 92, Folder 22)
    - Pittsburgh Nonprofit Summit, 2008 (Box 92, Folder 23)
    - Pittsburgh Press Strike, 1992 (Box 92, Folder 24)
    - Pittsburgh Pastoral Institute, 1970 (Box 92, Folder 25)
    - Pittsburgh Theological Seminary, Center for Business, Religions, and Professions, 1992-1993 (Box 92, Folder 26)
    - Pittsburgh Theological Seminary, The Many Faces of Eve, 1973 (Box 92, Folder 27)
    - Pittsburgh Urban Magnet Project, "40 Under 40" Call Report, 2005 (Box 92, Folder 28)
    - Popovich, Zoran, 1971-1972 (Box 92, Folder 29)
    - Preservation Pennsylvania, 1991-1998 (Box 92, Folder 30)
    - Princeton University, "Princeton University Today: A Program for Women" Invitation, 1975 (Box 92, Folder 31)
    - Prisoner of War Prayer Day, 1970 (Box 92, Folder 32)
    - Proposal for New Organization for National Political Leadership, Draft, 1996 (Box 92, Folder 33)
    - Quinn, Thomas, 1969 (Box 92, Folder 34)
    - "Redd Up" Day for Mayor Bob O'Connor, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 35)
    - Regional Asset District, Newspaper Clippings, 1998 (Box 92, Folder 36)
    - Republican Campaign Textbook, 1920 (Box 92, Folder 37)
    - Richardson, Elliot, Luncheon at Duquesne Club, 1974 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Rider University, Women in Leadership Seminar, 1994 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1974-1976 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Rooney, Dan, 1998 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Run Baby Run, 2004-2008 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Scaife, Richard M., Correspondence and Messages, 1976-1979 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Scaife, Richard M., Foundation Reports, 1977-1982 (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Scaife, Richard M., Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1974-1985 (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Schweiker, Richard, 1977 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Scumacci, Francis "Letty", 1976-1979 (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Shared Interest, Million Ripples Gala Honoring Desmond Tutu, 2007 (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Smith, Nate, 1970-2011 (Box 93, Folder 12-13)
    - Squirrel Hill Urban Coalition, 1971-1974 (Box 93, Folder 14-15)
    - St. Vincent College, Threshold Seminars, 1989 (Box 93, Folder 16)
    - Stadium Funding, Correspondence, 1999 (Box 93, Folder 17)
    - Stadium Funding, "Plan B" Newspaper Clippings, 1998 (Box 93, Folder 18)
    - Strategic Air Command, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 19)
    - Strickland, Bill, 1996-2002 (Box 93, Folder 20)
    - Tribute to Billy Conn, 1990 (Box 93, Folder 21)
    - United Black Front, 1973-1974 (Box 93, Folder 22)
    - United Way of Pittsburgh, 1975 (Box 93, Folder 23)
    - United Way of Pittsburgh, Alexis De Tocqueville Society, 2005 (Box 93, Folder 24)
    - United Way of Pittsburgh, Community Builder's Salute to the Pittsburgh Steelers, 1998 (Box 93, Folder 25)
    - US-India Forum, 2001 (Box 93, Folder 26)
    - Vietnam Veterans, 1981 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Vietnam Veterans Leadership Program of Western Pennsylvania, Partners in Leadership Awards Dinner, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Voter Research, Guides from the Taft Institute for Two Party Government (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Waldman, Jay, 1981-1986 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - "War for Empire" Consortium, 2002 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Wecht, Cyril, 1973-2003 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Westminster Choir College, Invitation to Board of Trustees, Newspaper Clipping, 1973 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - White House Historical Association Catalog, c. 1990s (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Williams, Eddie, 1990 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Womankind Television Series, 1977 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Women in Leadership Roles, Newspaper Clippings and Notes, 1983-1992 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - Women in Politics, Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1992 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    - Women in Politics and Political Caucuses, 1973 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - Women in Public Service, Report, 1980 (Box 94, Folder 14)
    - Women Leaders' Summit, 1995 (Box 94, Folder 15)
    - Women's Bureau, 70th Anniversary Conference, 1990 (Box 94, Folder 16)
    - Women's Information Service and Exchange, 1979 (Box 94, Folder 17)
    - Women's Law Project, 2011 (Box 94, Folder 18)
    - Women's Philanthropy, Magazine Article, c.1990 (Box 94, Folder 19)
    - Women's Rights, Notes, 1985-1986 (Box 94, Folder 20)
    - Working Together Consortium, 1999-2000 (Box 94, Folder 21)
    - World Affairs Council of Pittsburgh, 1975 (Box 94, Folder 22)
    - WTAE, Women's Advisory Council, 1973 (Box 94, Folder 23)
    - YWCA, 140th Anniversary, 2009 (Box 94, Folder 24)
    - YWCA, Alvin Ailey City Center Dance Theater, 1974 (Box 94, Folder 25)
    - YWCA, "In Sisterhood" Event, Invitation, 2013 (Box 94, Folder 26)
    - YWCA, Membership Drive, 1974 (Box 94, Folder 27)
    - YWCA, "A Tribute to Women" Event, 1985 (Box 94, Folder 28)
    - YWCA, "Women and Politics" Event, 1970 (Box 94, Folder 29)
    - Zonta International, Women of the Month Nomination, 1975 (Box 94, Folder 30)
    - Zonta International, "Tea with Elsie Hillman" Event, 1996 (Box 94, Folder 31)
    - Zonta International, 1997 (Box 94, Folder 32)
- National Awareness, 1985-1993; VIII.
  Series VIII contains correspondence, newspaper articles, reports, meeting minutes, and other records relating to Elsie Hillman's involvement in various organizations aimed at promoting national awareness for a particular cause or topic. Throughout her career, Hillman was involved in a number of commissions and other institutions that while associated with politics, were non-political in nature.
  - Blair House Restoration Foundation, 1985-1987; 1.
    Subseries 1 contains correspondence, memoranda, meeting minutes, and other records detailing Elsie Hillman's involvement in the Blair House Restoration Foundation. The Foundation was formed in order to help restoration and refurnishing of the Blair House, the Vice-Presidential residence.
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1985-1987 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Council and Committee Membership List, c. 1985 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Restoration Fundraising and Contributions, c. 1985 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Blair House Luncheon, 1985 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Equipment and Furnishings to be Restored, 1986 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Meeting Minutes and Related Materials, 1985-1986 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Commission on the Bicentennial of the United States Constitution, 1985-1986; 2.
    Subseries 2 contains correspondence, reports, articles, and other records relating Elsie Hillman's activity and interest on the Commission on the Bicentennial of the United States Constitution. The organization was largely focused on raising awareness of the United States Constitution's upcoming bicentennial in 1987 through activities such as commemorative events.
    - Bicentennial Alerts, 1986 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Commission Guidelines and Contact Information, 1985 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Reports and Articles, 1985-1986 (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Committee on the Constitutional System, 1985-1986; 3.
    Subseries 3 contains correspondence, reports, memoranda, and other records relating to Elsie Hillman's interest and involvement on the Committee on the Constitutional System. The committee, working around the bicentennial of the United States Constitution worked to generate interest in Constitutional reform, working to promote a more efficient government.
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - Financial Report, 1986 (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - Government in Gridlock Conference Schedule, 1993 (Box 95, Folder 13)
    - Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Notes, 1986 (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - Memoranda, 1986-1993 (Box 95, Folder 15-16)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1985-1986 (Box 95, Folder 17)
    - Statements, Reports, and Proposal, 1985-1986 (Box 95, Folder 18)
  - White House Endowment Fund, 1990-1993; 4.